comindware.com 2019-04-10

# Comindware Privacy Policy

_Effective Date: May 24, 2018_

At Comindware, we know you care about how your personal data is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. Please, read the following to learn more about how we collect, store, use and share your personal data and what choices you have about it. This Privacy Policy applies when you use our website.

## What Personal Data does Comindware Collect?

### Information You Provide to Us:

We may collect personal data that you choose to send to us or provide to us, for example, on our “Request a Demo”, “Get in Touch” or similar online form. If you contact us through the websites, we will keep a record of our correspondence.

### Data We Automatically Collect:

We may use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened by recipients. These data are used to enable more accurate reporting, improve the effectiveness of our marketing, and make our website better for our users.

Our website also uses cookies (small text files containing anonymous information about users) to uniquely identify your browser and to gather information about how you interact with the website. Please, check our Cookies Policy for more information about the categories of cookies that we use and why.

## How Do We Use the Data?

We will use the data we collect via our website:

  * To administer our website and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis and testing purposes;
  * Analyze customers’ use of the website for trend monitoring, marketing and advertising purposes;
  * Analyze customers’ use of the website for trend monitoring, marketing and advertising purposes;
  * For purposes made clear to you at the time you submit your information – for example, to fulfill your request for a demo or to provide you with information you have requested about our product;
  * As part of our efforts to keep our website safe and secure.

All the data you provide us with is used for Comindware business process exclusively. For this purposes we can share your data with 3rd parties but only in case all the security measures those 3rd parties take are as strong and strict as ours and only in case the data are used for Comindware business process purposes and to better assist you. For example, we may share your data with our payment processing providers, communication tool providers (e.g. JivoChat), CRM service providers (e.g., Salesforce), email marketing service providers (e.g., MailChimp), email validation (e.g., KickBox) and others. We can also share data with our business partners. You can receive communication from us or our business partners, from time to time, through e-mail, physical mail or by phone. Both service providers and business partners will have access to your data as reasonably necessary to perform their tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for other purposes.

## How do We Share and Disclose Data   
to Third Parties?

All the data you provide us with is used for Comindware business process exclusively. For this purposes we can share your data with 3rd parties but only in case all the security measures those 3rd parties take are as strong and strict as ours and only in case the data are used for Comindware business process purposes and to better assist you. For example, we may share your data with our payment processing providers, communication tool providers (e.g. JivoChat), CRM service providers (e.g., Salesforce), email marketing service providers (e.g., MailChimp), email validation (e.g., KickBox) and others. We can also share data with our business partners. You can receive communication from us or our business partners, from time to time, through e-mail, physical mail or by phone. Both service providers and business partners will have access to your data as reasonably necessary to perform their tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for other purposes.

## Is My Personal Data Secure?

We implement security safeguards designed to protect your data, such as HTTPS. We regularly monitor our systems for possible vulnerabilities and attacks. Unfortunately, no company or service can guarantee complete security. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user data at any time. Among other practices, your account is protected by a password for your privacy and security. You must prevent unauthorized access to your account and personal data by limiting access to your computer or device and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account.

## How Long do Comindware Keep   
Your Personal Data?

We keep your personal data only so long as we need it to fulfill the purposes described in this policy. This is also the case for anyone that we share your personal data with and who carries out services on our behalf. When we no longer need to use your data and there is no need for us to keep it to comply with our legal or regulatory obligations, we’ll either remove it from our systems or depersonalize it so that we can't identify you.

## Transferring Your Personal Data

### What Choices Do I Have?

You can always opt not to disclose personal data to us, but keep in mind some data may be needed to register with us or to take advantage of some of our services.

#### Marketing Communications

You can opt-out of receiving certain marketing communications from us at any time, by using the unsubscribe link in the emails communications we send.

#### Cookies

You can accept or reject cookies through our Privacy Preference Centre, accessible by clicking the “cookie settings” button in our cookie policy. You can also do so by adjusting your web browser controls. Please, consult our Cookies Policy for more information about our use of cookies and how to accept and reject them.

### How Can I Review, Update or Delete My Personal Data?

You have options in relation to the information that we have about you described below. To exercise these options, please contact us. If you're an European Economic Area (EEA) user, you can:

  * Access the information we hold about you. We'll usually share this with you within 30 days of you asking us for it.
  * Have your personal data corrected or deleted. You can ask us to delete, change, update or fix your data in certain cases, particularly if it’s inaccurate.
  * Object to, or Limit or Restrict, Use of Data: You can ask us to stop using all or some of your personal data (e.g., if we have no legal right to keep using it) or to limit our use of it (e.g., if your personal data is inaccurate or unlawfully held).

If you would like to review, update, rectify, or delete any personal data we hold about you, or exercise any other data subject right available to you under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), you can contact us.

Our privacy team will examine your request and respond to you as quickly as possible! Please, note that we may still use any aggregated and de-identified personal data that does not identify any individual, and may also retain and use your data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Transferring Your Personal Data

Personal data you submit on the website may be sent to the United States, if so, it will be primarily processed by the third-party agents in the United States who assist Comindware in providing services to its customers and prospective customers. Before disclosing personal data to a third-party agent, Comindware will obtain assurances from the recipient that it will: (a) use the personal data only to assist Comindware in providing the services; (b) belongs to the Privacy Shield; and (c) notify Comindware if the recipient is no longer able to provide the required protections. Upon notice, Comindware will act promptly to stop and remediate unauthorized processing of personal data by a recipient. Comindware will remain liable for onward transfers to its third-party agents.

## Contact Information

If you have questions or complaints regarding this Policy, the best way to get in touch is through the online contact form. Besides, if you live in the United States, you can contact Comindware at Foxboro, MA 02035, US. If you live outside the United States, please, contact Comindware at 157 Dmitrovskoje HWY, Unit 5, Moscow, Russia 127247.

## Will Comindware Ever Change This Privacy Policy?

We’re constantly trying to improve our website, so we may need to change this Privacy Policy from time to time as well. We will alert you to material changes by placing a notice on our Website, when we are required to do so by applicable law. You can see when this Privacy Policy was last updated by checking the date at the top of this page. You are responsible for periodically reviewing this Privacy Policy.
